<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/</id>
    <title>An Open Source Apache MQTT Broker | Apache BifroMQ (Incubating) Blog</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/"/>
    <subtitle>An Open Source Apache MQTT Broker | Apache BifroMQ (Incubating) Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://bifromq.apache.org/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Apache BifroMQ 4.0.0-incubating]]></title>
        <id>https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/announcing-apache-bifromq-4-0-0-incubating/</id>
        <link href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/announcing-apache-bifromq-4-0-0-incubating/"/>
        <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the availability of Apache BifroMQ 4.0.0-incubating, the project's first release in the Apache Incubator.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce the availability of Apache BifroMQ 4.0.0-incubating, the project's first release in the Apache Incubator.</p>
<p>This release marks an important milestone: it represents the transition of BifroMQ's pre-Apache development history and production experience into an Apache-governed project, with community-driven development, transparent processes, and formal release procedures.</p>
<p>This blog post provides a high-level overview of the release. For full details, please refer to the official release notes and latest online documents.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="what-this-release-represents">What this release represents<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/announcing-apache-bifromq-4-0-0-incubating/#what-this-release-represents" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What this release represents" title="Direct link to What this release represents" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Before entering the Apache Incubator, BifroMQ evolved as an internal system and later as an open-source project driven by a small group of maintainers. Joining the Apache Incubator changes the project in several important ways:</p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Community over individuals or organizations:</strong> Development, design decisions, and releases are discussed and decided on public mailing lists under the Apache way.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Formalized release process:</strong> Artifacts are produced, voted on, and published according to Apache's policies, with clear provenance and verification procedures.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Clear licensing and branding:</strong> The project adopts Apache License 2.0 and aligns with Apache's branding and trademark guidelines.</li>
</ul>
<p>Version 4.0.0-incubating is the first release that fully reflects this transition. It continues the technical lineage of earlier versions but should be considered a major upgrade from a user's perspective.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="highlights-in-400-incubating">Highlights in 4.0.0-incubating<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/announcing-apache-bifromq-4-0-0-incubating/#highlights-in-400-incubating" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Highlights in 4.0.0-incubating" title="Direct link to Highlights in 4.0.0-incubating" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>This release focuses on consolidating the architecture, improving operational capabilities, and preparing the project for broader adoption. Key highlights include:</p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Independent workload cluster deployment mode:</strong> MQTT frontends, distribution services, session storage, and other components can run as separate workload clusters so operators can scale and allocate resources independently based on workload characteristics.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Extensible client balancing:</strong> A new client balancer plugin interface enables custom strategies for distributing client connections across nodes or clusters, which is particularly useful in multi-region and multi-tenant environments.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Additional extension points for deep customization:</strong> More SPIs and hook points have been introduced across the stack to support deep customization and secondary development within BifroMQ.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Operational improvements:</strong> Enhancements to metrics, logging, and administrative APIs support observability, troubleshooting, and automation.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="compatibility-and-upgrade-notes">Compatibility and upgrade notes<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/announcing-apache-bifromq-4-0-0-incubating/#compatibility-and-upgrade-notes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Compatibility and upgrade notes" title="Direct link to Compatibility and upgrade notes" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Due to substantial internal refactoring and adjustments required to meet Apache Incubator requirements, 4.0.0-incubating is not backward-compatible with previous non-Apache releases of BifroMQ. If you are running a pre-Incubator version of BifroMQ, treat this as a major upgrade:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Test 4.0.0-incubating in a separate environment first.</li>
<li class="">Review the release notes for behavior changes that affect your deployment.</li>
<li class="">Plan any configuration or operational adjustments before switching production traffic.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/announcing-apache-bifromq-4-0-0-incubating/#acknowledgements" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Acknowledgements" title="Direct link to Acknowledgements" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>We would like to thank everyone who contributed code, reviews, testing, and feedback, as well as the Apache Incubator mentors and community members who helped guide the project through the initial steps of incubation.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Yonny(Yu) Hao</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/popduke</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Apache" term="Apache"/>
        <category label="BifroMQ" term="BifroMQ"/>
        <category label="MQTT" term="MQTT"/>
        <category label="Incubator" term="Incubator"/>
        <category label="Release" term="Release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Apache BifroMQ (Incubating)]]></title>
        <id>https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/</id>
        <link href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/"/>
        <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When teams move from a few thousand devices to millions of always-on connections, MQTT usually becomes a key piece of infrastructure. It offers a simple publish/subscribe model, works well on constrained networks, and has wide client support.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When teams move from a few thousand devices to millions of always-on connections, MQTT usually becomes a key piece of infrastructure. It offers a simple publish/subscribe model, works well on constrained networks, and has wide client support.</p>
<p>But at cloud scale, the broker itself turns into frontline infrastructure: it is the entry point for business traffic, it must handle massive numbers of long-lived connections, and it has to remain reliable under bursty and unpredictable workloads.</p>
<p>Apache BifroMQ (Incubating) was built in this environment. In this post, we give a high-level overview of what BifroMQ is, why another MQTT broker is needed, and how its architecture is shaped by real large-scale IoT deployments.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="what-is-apache-bifromq-incubating">What is Apache BifroMQ (Incubating)?<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#what-is-apache-bifromq-incubating" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is Apache BifroMQ (Incubating)?" title="Direct link to What is Apache BifroMQ (Incubating)?" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>Apache BifroMQ (Incubating) is a high-performance, distributed, Java-based MQTT broker, designed from the ground up for cloud systems rather than single-node or small-cluster deployments.</p>
<p>At a glance:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Standards-compliant MQTT</strong><br>
<!-- -->Full support for MQTT 3.1, 3.1.1, and 5.0.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Native multi-tenancy</strong><br>
<!-- -->Resource and workload isolation for multiple tenants sharing the same physical cluster.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Elastic scalability</strong><br>
<!-- -->Horizontally scalable for both concurrent connections and message throughput.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Built-in distributed state store</strong><br>
<!-- -->A storage layer optimized for MQTT-specific workloads such as persistent sessions, inflight messages, and retained data.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>BifroMQ currently resides in the Apache Incubator. As an incubating project, it follows the Apache way: open governance, community-driven decision-making, and formal release processes.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="why-another-mqtt-broker">Why another MQTT broker?<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#why-another-mqtt-broker" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why another MQTT broker?" title="Direct link to Why another MQTT broker?" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>While existing brokers serve a wide range of scenarios, BifroMQ is built around a particular architectural viewpoint: the MQTT broker itself can and should be engineered as a dedicated, distributed system with clear boundaries and responsibilities.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="mqtt-at-the-frontline">MQTT at the frontline<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#mqtt-at-the-frontline" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to MQTT at the frontline" title="Direct link to MQTT at the frontline" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<img src="https://bifromq.apache.org/assets/images/mqtt-at-the-frontline-74c1318615720635edc4f0cfdaf2328a.png" style="width:100%">
<p>In large deployments, the MQTT broker is not simply a protocol endpoint. It sits at the frontline between the internet or intranet and downstream systems:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">It must sustain massive numbers of long-lived client connections.</li>
<li class="">It must provide low-latency, bidirectional communication.</li>
<li class="">It must tolerate sudden bursts of traffic, such as when a large fleet reconnects after an outage or a firmware rollout.</li>
</ul>
<p>In this role, the broker behaves more like a core piece of cloud infrastructure than a traditional message queue.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="limitations-of-common-approaches">Limitations of common approaches<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#limitations-of-common-approaches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Limitations of common approaches" title="Direct link to Limitations of common approaches" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>In practice, platform teams often try three patterns:</p>
<ol>
<li class="">
<p><strong>MQTT adapters over something else</strong><br>
<!-- -->Implement MQTT as an adapter on top of another protocol or messaging system.<br>
<em>Pros</em>: reuses existing infrastructure.<br>
<em>Cons</em>: protocol translation friction, limited control over connection-level behavior, and an impedance mismatch between MQTT workloads and the underlying system.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>All-in-one IoT platforms</strong><br>
<!-- -->Use a monolithic platform where MQTT is tightly embedded.<br>
<em>Pros</em>: integrated feature set.<br>
<em>Cons</em>: strong coupling makes it harder to evolve the MQTT layer independently and often increases operational burden.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Non-clustered or single-tenant brokers</strong><br>
<!-- -->Run multiple broker instances for different products or tenants.<br>
<em>Pros</em>: simple to start.<br>
<em>Cons</em>: lack of multi-tenant support, weak or absent clustering, and difficulty in managing shared capacity at scale.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>These approaches often fall short when multiple tenants need to share the same infrastructure with clear isolation, fleets grow into tens of millions of devices, or operational teams aim for serverless-like elasticity on the data plane while the control plane (identity, billing, policy) remains decoupled.</p>
<p>BifroMQ takes a different angle: it is <strong>MQTT-only</strong>, <strong>designed for integration</strong>, and <strong>operations-oriented</strong>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="the-broker-first-approach">The broker-first approach<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#the-broker-first-approach" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The broker-first approach" title="Direct link to The broker-first approach" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>BifroMQ is built as a broker-first system:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">
<p><strong>MQTT-only, purpose-built</strong><br>
<!-- -->The system focuses on MQTT workloads instead of being a generic message bus. This allows optimizations that are difficult in multi-protocol systems.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Multi-tenancy as a core design</strong><br>
<!-- -->Tenants share physical resources but have isolated workloads, making it easier to host many customers or internal business units on the same cluster.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Designed for integration</strong><br>
<!-- -->Control-plane concerns (authentication, authorization, tenant management, billing) are integrated through plugins and APIs, rather than hard-coded into the broker. The data plane remains focused on MQTT.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Operations-aware</strong><br>
<!-- -->Self-healing mechanisms, customizable load-scheduling strategies, and decentralized control help keep the system available under failure and load spikes.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The goal is to make BifroMQ a strong building block for IoT platforms and internal device backbones, rather than a monolithic platform itself.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="architecture-highlights">Architecture highlights<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#architecture-highlights" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Architecture highlights" title="Direct link to Architecture highlights" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>BifroMQ's architecture reflects its focus on scale, multi-tenancy, and operations.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="decentralized-two-tier-clustering">Decentralized two-tier clustering<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#decentralized-two-tier-clustering" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Decentralized two-tier clustering" title="Direct link to Decentralized two-tier clustering" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<img src="https://bifromq.apache.org/assets/images/two-tier-clustering-73c330259ba1c8b0dfb99c974dcd3095.png" style="width:40%">
<p>At a high level, BifroMQ distinguishes between two logical layers:</p>
<ol>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Host cluster (underlay)</strong><br>
<!-- -->Represents the physical cluster composed of BifroMQ processes. It uses gossip-based failure detection to track node health and CRDT-based anti-entropy for membership and metadata convergence. The underlay provides a logically addressable substrate on which services run.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Agent clusters (overlay)</strong><br>
<!-- -->Represent logical service clusters that run within each BifroMQ process (for example, MQTT service, distribution service, inbox service, retain service). They communicate using a mix of peer-to-peer and broadcast patterns and also employ CRDT-based metadata synchronization.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This separation decouples engineering logic from the runtime environment. Deployment becomes flexible: you can run different services together or apart, depending on workload. There is no single point of failure for control; the system favors decentralized coordination and self-healing.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="workload-independent-architecture">Workload-independent architecture<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#workload-independent-architecture" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Workload-independent architecture" title="Direct link to Workload-independent architecture" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<img src="https://bifromq.apache.org/assets/images/workload-independent-architecture-6607eb201f72960ebc8ec013e82033ed.png" style="width:50%">
<p>Several internal services correspond to different aspects of MQTT behavior:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">
<p><strong>MQTT Service</strong><br>
<!-- -->Handles client connections, protocol parsing, and basic session management.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Distribution Service</strong><br>
<!-- -->Manages routing of published messages to subscribers across nodes and tenants.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Inbox Service</strong><br>
<!-- -->Deals with queued messages and persistent sessions.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Retain Service</strong><br>
<!-- -->Handles retained messages and their lifecycle.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>A key design goal is workload independence: each service can scale and evolve based on the specific resource profile it needs (CPU, memory, storage, network).</p>
<p>This enables deployment patterns such as on-demand workload scale-out, hybrid workload deployments, and independent workload clusters with dedicated resources and lifecycle.</p>
<img src="https://bifromq.apache.org/assets/images/workload-migration-944ec9fa35656058500995c0e8cb8067.png" style="width:75%">
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="extensibility-plugins-spis-and-apis">Extensibility: plugins, SPIs, and APIs<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#extensibility-plugins-spis-and-apis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Extensibility: plugins, SPIs, and APIs" title="Direct link to Extensibility: plugins, SPIs, and APIs" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>In real deployments, the MQTT broker must be integrated into a broader ecosystem:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Device identity and credential management</li>
<li class="">Authorization and policy engines</li>
<li class="">Billing, quota, and tenant administration</li>
<li class="">External control planes and automation tools</li>
</ul>
<p>BifroMQ addresses this with a set of extension mechanisms:</p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Plugins</strong> provide integration points for authentication, authorization, client balancing, and other behaviors that vary between environments.</li>
<li class=""><strong>SPIs</strong> are the primary mechanism for deep customization and secondary development, allowing advanced users to plug in their own implementations for key behaviors without modifying the broker core.</li>
<li class=""><strong>HTTP APIs and control endpoints</strong> allow external systems such as a cloud control panel or internal platform to manage tenants, configurations, and operational actions through well-defined interfaces.</li>
</ul>
<p>The intent is to keep the MQTT data plane stable and focused, while still making it straightforward to adapt BifroMQ to different organizational and business requirements.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="roadmap-and-what-is-next">Roadmap and what is next<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#roadmap-and-what-is-next" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Roadmap and what is next" title="Direct link to Roadmap and what is next" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>The project roadmap can be viewed in two dimensions:</p>
<ol>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Core project</strong><br>
<!-- -->Runtime efficiency and performance tuning, integration and extensibility improvements, and operational resilience including self-healing and adaptive scheduling.</p>
</li>
<li class="">
<p><strong>Satellite projects</strong><br>
<!-- -->Website, documentation, and blog content; tooling such as GUI or CLI for operations; load simulation and benchmarking tools; and plugins for specific industry scenarios.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>As an Apache Incubator project, BifroMQ's roadmap is expected to evolve with community input. Early adopters, operators, and contributors can have a significant impact on priorities.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_zVyf" id="getting-involved">Getting involved<a href="https://bifromq.apache.org/blog/introducing-apache-bifromq/#getting-involved" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Getting involved" title="Direct link to Getting involved" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>If BifroMQ matches challenges you face in your own IoT or device connectivity platform, there are several ways to get involved:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Try out the latest Apache Incubator release in a test environment.</li>
<li class="">Explore the architecture and design documents to see how it fits your stack.</li>
<li class="">Join the mailing lists to ask questions, share experience, or propose improvements.</li>
<li class="">Contribute bug reports, documentation, tests, or code.</li>
</ul>
<p>Apache BifroMQ (Incubating) aims to be a practical, operations-friendly MQTT broker for large-scale, multi-tenant workloads. We look forward to feedback and collaboration from the wider community as the project grows.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Yonny(Yu) Hao</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/popduke</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Apache" term="Apache"/>
        <category label="BifroMQ" term="BifroMQ"/>
        <category label="MQTT" term="MQTT"/>
        <category label="Multi-Tenant" term="Multi-Tenant"/>
        <category label="Serverless" term="Serverless"/>
        <category label="Decentralized Cluster" term="Decentralized Cluster"/>
    </entry>
</feed>